<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dynamical systems on epsilon dumblog</title>
    <link>/tags/dynamical-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dynamical systems on epsilon dumblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:30:17 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/dynamical-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buddhabrot, domain coloring, fractal flames and nevroses</title>
      <link>/blog/buddhalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:30:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/buddhalog/</guid>
      <description>For the past year or so, I have been working on a buddhabrot using the lambda function, defined by
$$ f_r(z) = r * z * (1 - z) $$
With \(r, z \in \mathbb C\). The goal initially was to simply compute an image (which I will refer to by the Buddhalog from now on) using the Buddhabrot technique, created by Melinda Green. A buddhabrot is a way to show the trajectories of points under iteration of a map: it&amp;rsquo;s an histogram of trajectories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Bifurcation Diagrams and Hilbert Curves</title>
      <link>/blog/complexbifmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 16:29:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/complexbifmap/</guid>
      <description>Bifurcation diagrams A bifurcation diagram is a pretty great way to observe the dynamics of a parametrized one dimensional map. On the x-axis, the parameter and on the y axis is shown the trajectory of the point after a few iteration (so that the system settle down into the attractor). For example, with the logistic map :
$$x_{n+1} = r * x_{n} (1 - x_{n}), r, x_0 \in \mathbb[R] $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blancmange</title>
      <link>/blog/blancmange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:16:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/blancmange/</guid>
      <description>Another short and sweet post on some pathological curve that I spent a good afternoon coding back in 2018. It&amp;rsquo;s called a &amp;ldquo;Blancmange curve&amp;rdquo; apparently in relation to some french cake. Well I&amp;rsquo;m French and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever eaten any self similar cakes. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sounds that good actually.Cake or not, the code is available here.
Anyway, this curve is defined as an infinite sum of smaller and smaller triangle waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bifurcation Diagrams</title>
      <link>/blog/biffmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:49:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/biffmap/</guid>
      <description>This time we&amp;rsquo;re gonna talk about things I know a little bit more about : bifurcation diagrams and iterated functions. The code is available here
Bifurcation diagrams show the behavior of a function \( f: \mathbb{R} \rightarrow \mathbb{R} \), with a real parameter under iteration. Iteration simply means &amp;ldquo;plugging the output into the input&amp;rdquo;: a feedback if you will. Iterating from a &amp;ldquo;seed&amp;rdquo; \(p\), the function can converge to a value (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
