<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math on epsilon dumblog</title>
    <link>/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in math on epsilon dumblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:04:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arnold and its Tongues</title>
      <link>/blog/tongues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:04:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tongues/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m back. I have been working a lot on my Indra&amp;rsquo;s Pearl implementation, available here. I&amp;rsquo;ll write an article about it soon, since it&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting, but not now. Now we&amp;rsquo;re talking about tongues. Code is available here
The Arnold Tongue(s) are a particular kind of fractal that arises when we plot the rotation number of a particular circle map. Circle maps are functions from the circle to itself. They are particularly conducive to chaotic motions, and are pretty simple so it&amp;rsquo;s a good start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devil&#39;s Staircase</title>
      <link>/blog/devilstaircase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 21:27:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/devilstaircase/</guid>
      <description>Today, just a quickie. The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Staircase (or Cantor Function) is a particular &amp;ldquo;pathological&amp;rdquo; function. It grows from 0 to 1 as \(x\) goes from 0 to 1, but it&amp;rsquo;s derivative are 0 almost everywhere. Meaning, that everywhere you zoom, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a flat line. Yet it goes up. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s flat almost everywhere ! Code? Here!.
Here, we generate the Devil&amp;rsquo;s Staircase using a particular Circle Map
$$\phi_{n+1} = \phi_n - \frac{K * sin(2 * \pi * phi_n)}{2 * \pi} $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos in Logic</title>
      <link>/blog/chaoticlogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:13:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/chaoticlogic/</guid>
      <description>Keeping up with the traditions I&amp;rsquo;ve set-up a few days ago, we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about chaos. &amp;ldquo;Oh no, yet another boring example of a Henon map ? Maybe with colors this time ? Or just the Lorentz Attractor with some platitudes on the chaos in life itself ?&amp;rdquo;, you may say, snarkily. Well, voices in my head, no, not quite.
I kinda dig logic as a field. And by &amp;ldquo;dig&amp;rdquo;, I mean looking from afar and vaguely nodding when someones talks to me about consistency of a formal system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bifurcation Diagrams</title>
      <link>/blog/biffmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:49:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/biffmap/</guid>
      <description>This time we&amp;rsquo;re gonna talk about things I know a little bit more about : bifurcation diagrams and iterated functions. The code is available here
Bifurcation diagrams show the behavior of a function \( f: \mathbb{R} \rightarrow \mathbb{R} \), with a real parameter under iteration. Iteration simply means &amp;ldquo;plugging the output into the input&amp;rdquo;: a feedback if you will. Iterating from a &amp;ldquo;seed&amp;rdquo; \(p\), the function can converge to a value (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussians Primes</title>
      <link>/blog/gaussints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 18:54:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gaussints/</guid>
      <description>On this second episode of &amp;ldquo;what has Epsilon done for the past years&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;re gonna talk about&amp;hellip; Prime Numbers. Code is available here.
The primes does have this capacity to create some interesting looking things, I&amp;rsquo;ll give them that. The Gaussian integers are simply complex numbers whose real and imaginary part are integers, and whose modulus is prime. If one component of this number p is 0, then p is prime only if the other component is prime and p % 4 = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ulam Spiral</title>
      <link>/blog/ullam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 18:38:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ullam/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first part of an attempt at explaining most of the small animations I have done in the past few years.
The Ulam Spiral is fairly straight forward: by arranging the integers in a spiral, and only marking the primes, you obtain strange, and frankly cool looking patterns.
Creating this sort of image is very simple. I simply created a basic loop that construct the spiral, which follows the following pattern: ULDDRRRUUUULLLL&amp;hellip;, assigning an integer to each step and checking if it was prime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
