<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fractals on epsilon dumblog</title>
    <link>/tags/fractals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fractals on epsilon dumblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:23:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/fractals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indras Pearl III : Searching for a place to stop</title>
      <link>/blog/indraspearl_pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:23:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/indraspearl_pt3/</guid>
      <description>In the past article we&amp;rsquo;ve seen an overview of what kind of objects we were talking about, and how to create generators that would be interesting to explore. In this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the bread and butter of Indra&amp;rsquo;s Pearl, namely the Depth First Exploration Algorithm, or DFS. For the sake of simplicity, i&amp;rsquo;ll refer to the inverse of a generator using the uppercase version of it&amp;rsquo;s associated letter, so the inverse of a is A, and the inverse of b is B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indras Pearl II: Generating the Generators</title>
      <link>/blog/indraspearl_pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 17:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/indraspearl_pt2/</guid>
      <description>This post is a part of a series where I try to explain my work on implementing methods from the book &amp;ldquo;Indra&amp;rsquo;s Pearl&amp;rdquo;, from Mumford, Series and Wright. In the first part I talked about the very basics. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it, simply because I really like it, and also because you might not understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.
In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how we chose the specific Möbius Transform that we&amp;rsquo;ll use for our exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indra&#39;s Pearl, or Quasifuschian Two Generator Groups explained by someone completely out of his depths</title>
      <link>/blog/indraspearl_pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:47:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/indraspearl_pt1/</guid>
      <description>A few months back I started reading Indra&amp;rsquo;s Pearl by Mumford, Series and Wright. The book is amazing, and I&amp;rsquo;m not scared to say it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite books about Maths that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. I wanted to get my hands dirty and implement some of the fractals in the book, since they were very different from the usual &amp;ldquo;Mandelbrot and cousins&amp;rdquo; fractals: they were truly out of this world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
